<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://thalesgroup.github.io/ciphertrust/blog</id>
    <title>CipherTrust Learn Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-04-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://thalesgroup.github.io/ciphertrust/blog"/>
    <subtitle>CipherTrust Learn Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://thalesgroup.github.io/ciphertrust/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Security without DevOps Disruption]]></title>
        <id>https://thalesgroup.github.io/ciphertrust/blog/Data Security in DevOps</id>
        <link href="https://thalesgroup.github.io/ciphertrust/blog/Data Security in DevOps"/>
        <updated>2023-04-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Note - this article was originally posted on Hal's blog on March 24, 2023 under the title "CipherTrust Transparent Encryption."]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Note - this article was originally posted on Hal's blog on March 24, 2023 under the title "CipherTrust Transparent Encryption."</p><p>In many organisations, IT departments are sometimes required to delegate some of their responsibilities to other teams, but at the same time, also required to keep control of the company security. Wait! In the world of security, can data security become a delegated responsibility? If that is a yes, then how?</p><p>Five years ago, I was pulled into the DevOps team culture and mindset. Since then, I have been lucky enough to manage the building of several DevOps teams. One of the many attributes of the DevOps culture is their autonomy. DevOps teams build in a way that can execute a task from end to end. The teams build up while working through the requirements and functions of the project or product, and with this knowledge, go on to find the most effective way of breaking the silos encountered by traditional teams.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a href="#introduction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Introduction" title="Direct link to Introduction">​</a></h3><p>The previous paragraph described DevOps as being about speed of delivery and autonomy, which also requires the team to access resources that are not always managed within the team; Active Directory, file shares, and so on are examples of these resources. So, how can you keep your DevOps team focused, but not affect the company processes?</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="scenario">Scenario<a href="#scenario" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Scenario" title="Direct link to Scenario">​</a></h3><p>Let’s put the DevOps information above into context using a real scenario I came across last week with one of the teams I help to build two years ago.</p><p>Company A was working on a confidential application for a client; the client was concerned that a breach of their code data would expose their intellectual property to competitors, or would become general knowledge.</p><p>The client asked that the following hierarchy be implemented to help mitigate their risk:</p><ul><li>Each Team has it own encrypted directory</li><li>Only the specific team can access and read the code</li><li>Admin can manage the files within all the directories, but cannot read the code</li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-challenge">The Challenge<a href="#the-challenge" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Challenge" title="Direct link to The Challenge">​</a></h3><p>From those requirements, Company A faces the following challenges:</p><ul><li>How to implement access management and encryption at the same time</li><li>How to avoid disruption of the DevOps team concept</li><li>Delegate security manageability to the DevOps team without affecting the wider company policy</li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="solution">Solution<a href="#solution" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Solution" title="Direct link to Solution">​</a></h3><p>Access management can be controlled using the company Active Directory; but doing so will complicate the workflow of the DevOps team and will slow the delivery. At the same time, Active Directory and Group Policies do not offer encryption, so the IT department turned to Thales CipherTrust Manager to solve this challenge.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="implementation">Implementation<a href="#implementation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Implementation" title="Direct link to Implementation">​</a></h3><p>To achieve all the security requirements, Company A decided to use CipherTrust Manager with the Transparent Encryption feature. Using Transparent Encryption Live Data Transformation (LDT), Company A can delegate the code data management to the DevOps team, but at the same time, encrypt the data and also keep Admin in control of managing and backing up the code files without compromising security.</p><p>So let’s learn how company A uses CipherTrust Manager to keep each team in control.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ciphertrust-user-and-domain">CipherTrust User and Domain<a href="#ciphertrust-user-and-domain" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to CipherTrust User and Domain" title="Direct link to CipherTrust User and Domain">​</a></h3><p>To delegate responsibilities, the Company A IT team was looking for a multi-tenanted system that can help the department to easily create and assign multiple teams to manage their own security requirements, while remaining isolated from each other. This requirement can be met with Thales CTM by creating a Domain to allow the DevOps team to manage their access control and security needs.</p><p>To create a Domain, you first create a user by browsing to <strong>“Access Management -&gt; Users -&gt; Add User“:</strong>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://ThalesGroup.github.io%5Cciphertrust%5Cstatic%5Cimg%5Cadduser.webp" alt="Add_User" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>After you have added the user, apply the user to <strong>CTE Admins and Clients</strong> by going to <strong>Edit/view</strong> the user. Under <strong>Groups</strong>, Search <strong>CTE</strong> and add to <strong>Admin/Client</strong>:
<img loading="lazy" src="https://ThalesGroup.github.io%5Cciphertrust%5Cstatic%5Cimg%5CCTE_Groups.webp" alt="CTE_Groups" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>The next step is to browse to “<strong>Admin Settings -&gt; Domains</strong>” and click “<strong>Add Domain</strong>“:</p><ul><li>Name: DevOps</li><li>Admins: devops (the user you just created)</li><li>Choose the default CA</li><li>Save
<img loading="lazy" src="https://ThalesGroup.github.io%5Cciphertrust%5Cstatic%5Cimg%5CAdd_Domain.webp" alt="Add_Domain" class="img_ev3q"></li></ul><p>Now you are ready to logout and then login with the user you just created. After logging in again, change the domain to the new domain at the top right corner – <strong>Switch Domains</strong>:
<img loading="lazy" src="https://ThalesGroup.github.io%5Cciphertrust%5Cstatic%5Cimg%5Cswitchdomains.webp" alt="Switch_Domains" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="create-a-key">Create a Key<a href="#create-a-key" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Create a Key" title="Direct link to Create a Key">​</a></h3><p>To be able to encrypt the data, we must create a key. Creating a key is very simple with CipherTrust Manager, all you need is to browse to the keys at the left menu and press the “<strong>Add key</strong>“. The next step is to provide a Key name: for example we will create a key name: <strong>LDT_Key</strong> and then press”<strong>Add Key</strong>” to save it.</p><p>At the next window, expand the “<strong>Key Access</strong>” option. On the search bar, type “<strong>CTE</strong>” with show all groups, then tick the check boxes for all the Admins and Clients permissions. Press <strong>Update</strong>:
<img loading="lazy" src="https://ThalesGroup.github.io%5Cciphertrust%5Cstatic%5Cimg%5Ckeyaccess.webp" alt="Key_Access" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Next, browse to “<strong>Key Labels -&gt; CTE</strong>“. Choose <strong>CBC</strong> from the drop down menu”. Press <strong>Update</strong>:
<img loading="lazy" src="https://ThalesGroup.github.io%5Cciphertrust%5Cstatic%5Cimg%5Ckeylabel.webp" alt="Key_Label" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="install-the-transparent-encryption-agent">Install the Transparent Encryption Agent<a href="#install-the-transparent-encryption-agent" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Install the Transparent Encryption Agent" title="Direct link to Install the Transparent Encryption Agent">​</a></h3><p>To be able to install and use the Transparent Encryption feature, you must install an agent. The first step is to create a “<strong>Registration Token</strong>“; this will be used during the agent installation to add the agent to the CipherTrust Manager. To create the Token, browse to “<strong>Access Management -&gt; Registration Tokens</strong>” and click on “<strong>Add Registration Token</strong>” and complete the following entries:</p><ul><li>Provide a Name Prefix: on my case DevOps_Token</li><li>Local CA: choose the default</li><li>Create a token: Base64
<img loading="lazy" src="https://ThalesGroup.github.io%5Cciphertrust%5Cstatic%5Cimg%5CCreatetoken.webp" alt="Create_Token" class="img_ev3q"></li></ul><p>Copy the token; then go to your Windows or Linux machine to run the agent installation. During the installation, you will be asked to provide:</p><ul><li>Componant to register: File System</li><li>CipherTrust Manager IP/Hostname</li><li>Enable LDT Feature (FS agent only)</li><li>Token</li></ul><p>After the installation is completed and you have successfully rebooted, you will be able to see the registered client on your CipherTrust Manager under: <strong>Transparent Encryption -&gt; Clients</strong>:
<img loading="lazy" src="https://ThalesGroup.github.io%5Cciphertrust%5Cstatic%5Cimg%5CCTE_Client.webp" alt="CTE_Client" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Creating Policies:</p><p>After deploying the agent and connecting it to the CTM, we can focus on creating our polices. As we have four different teams in our example, lets create four policies as shown below:</p><ul><li>DevOps_Admin_Team: Access and manage files and directories but can read files content</li><li>DevOps_Dev_Team: access only Development directory</li><li>DevOps_Ops_Policy: access only operation directory</li><li>DevOps_QA_Team: access only QA diretory</li></ul><p>Let’s create first policy, the <strong>DevOps_Admin_Team</strong> policy by browsing to “<strong>Transparent Encryption -&gt; Policies -&gt; Create policy</strong>“:</p><ul><li>Name: DevOps_Admin_Team</li><li>Policy Type: Live Data Transformation</li><li>Security Rules: + Create Security Rule<ul><li>User Set – Select – Create User Set:<ul><li>Name: Admin_Team</li><li>Create User<ul><li>Agent – select Agent</li><li>User Type: LDAP</li><li>Member Choice: User or Group (on my case I choose group)</li><li>gname: group name</li></ul></li><li>Note: repeat the above steps to create all the users for each group (i.e: Admin, Dev, Ops and QA team. on each time you need to create a policy you can easily choose the appropriate group or user)</li></ul></li><li>Action – Select<ul><li>All_Ops</li></ul></li><li>Effect – Select<ul><li>select permit</li><li>ApplyKey only of other group but not Admin group as the admin will not be able to unencrypt the data so a key not required</li></ul></li></ul></li><li>Key Rules: Create key Rule<ul><li>Current Key Name: Select – “clear_key”</li><li>Tranformation Key Name: Select – LTD_Key</li><li>Add</li></ul></li><li>Next – Confirmation – Save</li></ul><p>Note: repeat the above steps for all the groups</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="create-guardpoint">Create GuardPoint<a href="#create-guardpoint" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Create GuardPoint" title="Direct link to Create GuardPoint">​</a></h3><p>Our last step is to apply these policies to our folders or client. In this example, I will be using a Windows client. So let’s get started:</p><p>As we have different teams and policies, each with different access, we must create a different client <strong>GuardPoint</strong>. Browse to <strong>Transparent Encryption -&gt; Clients</strong>. Choose the client – “<strong>Create GuardPoint</strong>“:</p><ul><li>Select Policy: choose DevOps_QA_Team</li><li>Path: browse to the QA directory and select “select Path”</li><li>Create</li></ul><p>Note: repeat for each team and select the appropriate directory
<img loading="lazy" src="https://ThalesGroup.github.io%5Cciphertrust%5Cstatic%5Cimg%5Ccreateguardpoint.webp" alt="Create_GuardPoint" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>After all the directories are assigned to a group – on each GuardPoint – press the policy name and add the right action for each team as shown below; for example:</p><ul><li>Development_Team can access, and apply key</li><li>Operation_Team no access</li><li>Admin_Team access but no key
<img loading="lazy" src="https://ThalesGroup.github.io%5Cciphertrust%5Cstatic%5Cimg%5Cdevops_permission_group.webp" alt="DevOps_Permission_Group" class="img_ev3q"></li></ul><p>Note: repeat for all other GuardPoints</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="summary">Summary<a href="#summary" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Summary" title="Direct link to Summary">​</a></h3><p>After Following the steps described above, you can check that your new configuration works by accessing your Windows machine with a different user; for example, QA, dev, ops or admin, then check to see if you can access or read the files. The above steps are a little involved, more than Active Directory Group Policies; but with CipherTrust you also get the encryption aspect with a full and controlled separation of responsibilities.</p><p>Company A was able to achieve their client’s security request; but at the same time, did not affect the team processes, autonomy, and control. At both levels, Company A IT and DevOps, it was a win – win situation.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Hal Yaman (B.Sc)</name>
        </author>
        <category label="data-encryption" term="data-encryption"/>
        <category label="devops" term="devops"/>
        <category label="data-security" term="data-security"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide to Picking the Right Key Manager for Your Org]]></title>
        <id>https://thalesgroup.github.io/ciphertrust/blog/choosing-a-key-manager</id>
        <link href="https://thalesgroup.github.io/ciphertrust/blog/choosing-a-key-manager"/>
        <updated>2022-11-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your company has a ton of daily active users and you have this amazingly efficient architecture to process requests at scale, but your InfoSec team asks you to use a key manager — there are so many out there, which one do you choose?]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Your company has a ton of daily active users and you have this amazingly efficient architecture to process requests at scale, but your InfoSec team asks you to use a key manager — there are so many out there, which one do you choose?</p><p>There are various different types of key managers, but in this post, we’ll cover the three most common key managers:</p><ul><li><p>Native Cloud Key Managers (Ex — AWS KMS, GCP KMS, Azure Key Vault, etc.)</p></li><li><p>External Key Managers (Ex — Thales CipherTrust Manager, etc.)</p></li><li><p>Hybrid Key Managers (Use the best of both worlds — Cloud managed services and external key managers)</p></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="first-the-literal--key-to-security--hsms">First, the literal  key to security — HSMs<a href="#first-the-literal--key-to-security--hsms" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to First, the literal  key to security — HSMs" title="Direct link to First, the literal  key to security — HSMs">​</a></h2><p>HSM stands for “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hardware_security_module" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hardware Security Module</a>”. These are physical devices that are usually tamper resistant which store keys and perform encrypt, decrypt and other cryptographic operations.</p><p>HSMs are needed in secure environments such as healthcare or financial institutions where you need to pass compliances such as PCI DSS.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="now-lets-compare">Now Let’s Compare<a href="#now-lets-compare" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Now Let’s Compare" title="Direct link to Now Let’s Compare">​</a></h2><p>Let’s look at the pros and cons of each to help you decide what would work best for your organization.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="cloud-key-managers">Cloud Key Managers<a href="#cloud-key-managers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Cloud Key Managers" title="Direct link to Cloud Key Managers">​</a></h3><p>✅ <strong>Easy Integration with Cloud Managed Services</strong></p><p>When using cloud key managers like <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/kms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AWS KMS (Key Management Service)</a> it can be advantageous as you get the flexibility of AWS managing your keys as well as direct integration into your existing AWS managed services such as <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/s3/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AWS S3</a>, or <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/rods/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AWS RDS (Relational Database Service)</a>, etc.</p><p>✅ <strong>HSMs provisioned and managed by a cloud provider (most of the time 🤞)</strong></p><p>Most famous cloud providers have HSMs that they use in their data centers which store your keys, so you don’t have to worry about renting an HSM.</p><p><strong>❌ No Separation of Trust 🕵️‍♀️</strong></p><p>Since your cloud provider now hosts and controls your data and encryption keys. Your user data might not be as safe anymore as the cloud provider with malicious intent could easily decrypt your user data. This does not help in creating a <strong>zero-trust architecture</strong>. While it’s true that your cloud provider has your best interest; there are always hackers lurking around the internet trying to get malicious access to your data, so it’s best to store data in an isolated environment.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="external-key-managers">External Key Managers<a href="#external-key-managers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to External Key Managers" title="Direct link to External Key Managers">​</a></h3><p><strong>✅ Complete Separation of Trust</strong></p><p>When running a product such as CipherTrust Manager, your architectures are zero-trust by default as 2 different entities have access to either your data or your keys and <strong>NOT both</strong>.</p><p><strong>❌ Build your own custom integrations</strong></p><p>Unless the key manager service has connectors, many-a-times, you would need to build your own connectors which could put a lot of engineering debt on your teams.</p><p>⚠️<strong> Need to rent out your own HSM</strong></p><p>You’d need to manage your own HSM, but fortunately, there are service providers that will rent out and manage the HSMs (just like a cloud provider) — so this is neither a pro nor a con. A great example of a hosted HSM is the <a href="https://cpl.thalesgroup.com/encryption/data-protection-on-demand/services/luna-cloud-hsm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Luna HSM</a>.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="best-of-both-worlds-"><strong>Best of Both Worlds 🤔</strong><a href="#best-of-both-worlds-" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to best-of-both-worlds-" title="Direct link to best-of-both-worlds-">​</a></h2><p>Yes, it’s possible! To implement the best data security practices, you would want the ease of integration with cloud-managed services as well as complete separation of trust to isolate encryption keys from data. This method is also called <strong>BYOK </strong>(bring your own key).</p><p>You can do this with products such as CipherTrust Manager <a href="https://cpl.thalesgroup.com/encryption/key-management/ciphertrust-cloud-key-manager" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cloud Key Manager</a>. This offers:</p><p><strong>✅ Direct connection with cloud-managed KMS account</strong></p><p>Once you connect your AWS or GCP or Azure account to CipherTrust Manager as shown in the tutorial linked below, you will be able to manage keys directly from CipherTrust Manager and encrypt data on cloud-managed services.</p><p><strong>✅ Key Lifecycle Management in a few clicks</strong></p><p>In just a few clicks you can setup key rotation which will rotate your keys every few months and provide the best data security standards for your organization.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-do-i-implement-this">How do I implement this?<a href="#how-do-i-implement-this" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How do I implement this?" title="Direct link to How do I implement this?">​</a></h3><p>Luckily, it’s easy to implement in 3 simple steps. Here’s a tutorial I made that demos connecting CipherTrust Manager to my AWS KMS (Key Management Service) account and encrypt my AWS managed services such as S3 and RDS.</p><div class="video-responsive"><iframe width="853" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9Cs9s7DpJFU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" title="Embedded youtube"></iframe></div><div class="flex flex-row justify-between"></div><p>Now go ahead and encrypt all your cloud-managed services using this hybrid BYOK approach!</p><p>If you have any issues with implementation or questions about data encryption, go to the CipherTrust community and post <a href="https://supportportal.thalesgroup.com/community" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a quesiton</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Pranav Shikarpur</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/snpranav</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="data-encryption" term="data-encryption"/>
        <category label="key-management" term="key-management"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide to Data Security Architectures]]></title>
        <id>https://thalesgroup.github.io/ciphertrust/blog/a-guide-to-encryption-architectures</id>
        <link href="https://thalesgroup.github.io/ciphertrust/blog/a-guide-to-encryption-architectures"/>
        <updated>2022-10-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building and deploying applications and services is super exciting. Still, when your security team prevents your application from going into production due to a lack of data encryption — this can be very annoying.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Building and deploying applications and services is super exciting. Still, when your security team prevents your application from going into production due to a lack of data encryption — this can be very annoying.</p><p>Let’s take a look at the different data encryption methods that are most commonly used and how we can implement some of them.</p><h1>Data encrypted at-rest vs in-transit?</h1><p>Well, it’s often hard to choose between encrypting a complete Postgres database or encrypting only specific fields of data in the database right before it gets written to a table.</p><p>The key difference between the two is that encrypting a database <strong>after</strong> data is written to it is called <strong>data encryption at rest</strong> and encrypting data <strong>before</strong> data is written to a database is called data encryption <strong>in-transit</strong>.</p><p>The illustration below should give you a good high-level understanding of the difference. Although data encryption at-rest was a standard encryption practice followed for many years, it involves developers writing and maintaining various different scripts or applications to ensure that the encryption is up to company standards. It is still useful while encrypting file systems and storage. On the other hand, data encryption in-transit is a lot more beneficial at times when you want to make your infrastructure database agnostic and provide high-security standards with significantly low developer effort.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://miro.medium.com/max/720/1*7sOyc7n62Mxsq0cfKsLL0Q.png" alt="Data Encryption at REST Architecture" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Note that from the above diagram we can see that the method of encrypting data in-transit uses a <strong>side-car container</strong> which is a proxy used to intercept every request with sensitive fields or encrypted data and encrypt or decrypt the same respectively.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://miro.medium.com/max/720/1*9PC9Nv4j_L2LIoWsR4ZIeg.png" alt="Data Encryption in-transit Architecture" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="advantages-of-data-encryption-in-transit">Advantages of Data Encryption in-Transit<a href="#advantages-of-data-encryption-in-transit" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Advantages of Data Encryption in-Transit" title="Direct link to Advantages of Data Encryption in-Transit">​</a></h2><p><strong>✅ No change to applications</strong></p><p>The beauty of doing data-encryption in transit is that you don’t need to worry about changing any of your frontend apps, APIs, or databases. Since the side-car container does field-level encryption, you can granularly control all the data that needs to be encrypted and decrypted by remotely setting access policies from your key manager.</p><p><strong>✅ Easy to deploy</strong></p><p>Deploying a <a href="https://cpl.thalesgroup.com/encryption/ciphertrust-data-protection-gateway" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Protection Gateway</a> side-car container is as easy to deploy as logging agents such as DataDog or Prometheus. You can just update your docker-compose, Kubernetes config files or just use Helm to install it.</p><p><strong>✅ Developers can stop implementing data security policies</strong></p><p>Now you can shift the responsibility of setting and implementing data security policies from developers over to InfoSec teams. This significantly helps prevent data breaches or unauthorized data access.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="disadvantages-of-data-encryption-in-transit">Disadvantages of Data Encryption in-Transit<a href="#disadvantages-of-data-encryption-in-transit" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Disadvantages of Data Encryption in-Transit" title="Direct link to Disadvantages of Data Encryption in-Transit">​</a></h2><p>❌ <strong>Data encryption is only as strong as policies set</strong></p><p>This applies to any method of data encryption. However, when we perform field-level encryption and decryption, InfoSec teams need to be aware of all data flowing through various API routes to prevent data breaches and unauthorized access to unencrypted data.</p><hr><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-do-i-implement-data-encryption-in-transit">How Do I Implement Data Encryption in-Transit?<a href="#how-do-i-implement-data-encryption-in-transit" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How Do I Implement Data Encryption in-Transit?" title="Direct link to How Do I Implement Data Encryption in-Transit?">​</a></h2><p>You’re in luck 🙌 because I have a tutorial showing you how to easily implement data encryption in-transit with any of your containerized applications.</p><p>In this tutorial, I have used <a href="https://ciphertrust.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CipherTrust Manager</a>’s Data Protection Gateway product which is extremely easy to set up and free to start using👇</p><div class="video-responsive"><iframe width="853" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EJun5McPRGY" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" title="Embedded youtube"></iframe></div><div class="flex flex-row justify-between"><div><a href="https://github.com/ThalesGroup/learn-ciphertrust/tree/main/learn/dpg/data-encryption-in-transit-docker" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><button style="background-color:#171515" class="p-2 my-4 rounded-md border-none cursor-pointer text-white">GitHub <svg stroke="currentColor" fill="currentColor" stroke-width="0" viewBox="0 0 1024 1024" class="text-white" height="1em" width="1em" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M511.6 76.3C264.3 76.2 64 276.4 64 523.5 64 718.9 189.3 885 363.8 946c23.5 5.9 19.9-10.8 19.9-22.2v-77.5c-135.7 15.9-141.2-73.9-150.3-88.9C215 726 171.5 718 184.5 703c30.9-15.9 62.4 4 98.9 57.9 26.4 39.1 77.9 32.5 104 26 5.7-23.5 17.9-44.5 34.7-60.8-140.6-25.2-199.2-111-199.2-213 0-49.5 16.3-95 48.3-131.7-20.4-60.5 1.9-112.3 4.9-120 58.1-5.2 118.5 41.6 123.2 45.3 33-8.9 70.7-13.6 112.9-13.6 42.4 0 80.2 4.9 113.5 13.9 11.3-8.6 67.3-48.8 121.3-43.9 2.9 7.7 24.7 58.3 5.5 118 32.4 36.8 48.9 82.7 48.9 132.3 0 102.2-59 188.1-200 212.9a127.5 127.5 0 0 1 38.1 91v112.5c.8 9 0 17.9 15 17.9 177.1-59.7 304.6-227 304.6-424.1 0-247.2-200.4-447.3-447.5-447.3z"></path></svg></button></a></div><div><a href="https://main-yak.sneakpeak.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><button class="p-2 my-4 rounded-md border-none cursor-pointer">View Demo <svg stroke="currentColor" fill="currentColor" stroke-width="0" viewBox="0 0 1024 1024" height="1em" width="1em" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M869 487.8L491.2 159.9c-2.9-2.5-6.6-3.9-10.5-3.9h-88.5c-7.4 0-10.8 9.2-5.2 14l350.2 304H152c-4.4 0-8 3.6-8 8v60c0 4.4 3.6 8 8 8h585.1L386.9 854c-5.6 4.9-2.2 14 5.2 14h91.5c1.9 0 3.8-.7 5.2-2L869 536.2a32.07 32.07 0 0 0 0-48.4z"></path></svg></button></a></div></div><hr><p>Now go ahead and encrypt data in-transit from all your applications using side-car containers.</p><p>If you have any issues with implementation or questions about data encryption in-transit, feel free to leave a comment, tweet <a href="https://twitter.com/snpranav" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@snpranav</a>, or raise a <a href="https://github.com/ThalesGroup/learn-ciphertrust/issues/new" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub issue</a> :)</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Pranav Shikarpur</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/snpranav</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="data-encryption" term="data-encryption"/>
        <category label="data-protection-gateway" term="data-protection-gateway"/>
    </entry>
</feed>